<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FSAE on Samuel Petrina</title>
    <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/tags/fsae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FSAE on Samuel Petrina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samuel-petrina.github.io/tags/fsae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FSAE Steering System</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/fsae-steering-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/fsae-steering-system/</guid>
      <description>One particularly challenging subsystem of an FSAE car is the steering system. The primary reason for the difficulty is how close the front wheels are to the steering wheel. In a street car and most open-wheeled vehicles for that matter, the front wheels are well in front of the steering wheel meaning the steering rack and the steering wheel can be connected with a few universal joints. The classic FSAE solution in the past was to place the steering rack in-line with the upper control arm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSAE Control Arms</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/fsae-control-arms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/fsae-control-arms/</guid>
      <description>Wishbones after being tacked on jigging plate, ready to be welded
In previous years, our team has used carbon fiber control arms made by gluing aluminum lugs into the end of carbon tubing. This works quite well for tie-rods and pushrods where the lug is a simple cylindrical part with a tapped hole for rod-end bearings. The lugs for the wishbones however were a complex 4-axis milling job that caused issues for our team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSAE Uprights</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/fsae-uprights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/fsae-uprights/</guid>
      <description>Finished rear upright
Because our suspension geometry had changed significantly from our previous car, we needed to design and manufacture new front and rear uprights. Our primary goal for this year&amp;rsquo;s design was manufacturability. For us, this meant ensuring all features can be machined from just two milling machine setups. Our front geometry was similar to the previous design so we had the option to simply modify the old CAD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
