<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Woodworking on Samuel Petrina</title>
    <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/tags/woodworking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Woodworking on Samuel Petrina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samuel-petrina.github.io/tags/woodworking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loft Ladder</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/loft-ladder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/loft-ladder/</guid>
      <description>Ladder in stowed position
My aunt recently finished building her cottage on Galiano Island. To access the loft, she wanted a wooden ladder to replace the not-so-easy-on-the-eyes aluminum ladder that she had been using. Her main requirement was that she could move the ladder out of the way when not in use. This was accomplished using a slider rail at the top of the ladder. Because half the weight of the ladder is supported by the rail when the ladder is being moved, the ladder should be much more manageable to move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Construction for Romeo &amp; Juliet</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/set-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/set-construction/</guid>
      <description>Stairs a few nights before the play
In early 2020 my high school was putting on a production of Romeo &amp;amp; Juliet. Most of the stage equipment was provided by the school district, however, the stairs they had did not match the height of the stage. My close friend and I volunteered as we both had a few summers of construction experience. To figure out the stringer layout, I used CAD which made the whole process easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bent Lamination Field Hockey Stick</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/bent-lamination-field-hockey-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/bent-lamination-field-hockey-stick/</guid>
      <description>Finished hockey stick
After having decent success with sculptural woodworking projects like a canoe paddle, I wanted to do something more unique. I decided a field hockey stick would be a fun challenge. The issue with making a field hockey stick is the hook shape on the end. If you were to simply cut the stick out of a solid piece of wood, the hook would snap off with the slightest impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beavertail Style Canoe Paddle</title>
      <link>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/canoe-paddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samuel-petrina.github.io/posts/canoe-paddle/</guid>
      <description>Paddle after sanding but before the urethane finish
After seeing some beautiful beavertail paddles being sold at MEC, I was inspired to give making one a shot. The key distinguishing feature of a beavertail paddle is the narrow blade. This is traditionally done so the paddle can be made with a single reasonably sized board in the days before wood glue. Even though this isn&amp;rsquo;t relevant now, the style lives on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
